Guide to the Grace Cavalieri papers, 1945-2022 MS2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Magnetic audiotape reels, 1976-1985; Series 1
  - "Poetry from the City: M.L.K. Library; Leon Damas Special, Readings by Jessica Tarahata Hagedorn.", 11/10/1977 (Box 20A, Reel 365)
  - "Poetry from the City: Folio Bookstore; Adesanya Alekoye, Robert Hinton.", 12/02/1977 (Box 20A, Reel 366)
  - "Poetry from the City: Folio Bookstore; Adesanya Alekoye, Robert Hinton.", 12/02/1977 (Box 20A, Reel 367)
  - "Poetry from the City: Folio Bookstore; Adesanya Alekoye, Robert Hinton.", 12/02/1977 (Box 20A, Reel 368)
  - "Poetry from the City: Ken Hackten II.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 369)
    Note: "In the beginning of the tape, his poem had some imagination and expression. His voice is clear but monotone. He numbers his verses. At the beginning of each poems, he explains them. [Advisory for "sensitive words" also indicated.]
  - "Poetry from the City: Ron Rackter, Ann Lauderbach, Liam Rector.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 370)
    Note: "Greg Miles, Folio Bookstore--Poetry from the City. Ann Lauderbach--a New York Poet originally from England, gifted and colorfully descriptive. Ron Rackter--a local uniquely crafted poet, not published."
  - "Poetry from the City: Ron Rackter, Ann Lauderbach, Liam Rector.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 371)
  - "Poetry from the City: Linsberg.", n.d., undated (Box 20A, Reel 372)
    Note:"Poetry from the City--Linsberg. His poetry is like a ballad. He portrays the story like an actor instead of just reading it. He takes you on a trip, describes everything so visually that it leaves an impression of a picture in your mind. His poems are usually happy or spoken rapidly, excitedly. Every sentence rhymed almost like a fairy tale--rhyme--in that fashion. His poems are positive and his descriptions are colorful."
  - "Poetry from the City: Washington Women's Art Center; Tom Wells, Barbara Lefcowitz, Shirley Kaufman.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 373)
    Notes: "Bob Inger--Wells Poetry from the City, WWAC Washington Women's Art Center. This poet says his work was influenced by a lot of other poets and actors. His work is very captivating, but he could stand a little music in the background. He seems as if he has a great deal of understanding and knowledge."
  - "Poetry from the City: Washington Women's Art Center; Tom Wells, Barbara Lefcowitz, Shirley Kaufman.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 374)
  - "Poetry from the City: Washington Women's Art Center; Tom Wells, Barbara Lefcowitz, Shirley Kaufman.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 375)
  - "Poetry from the City: Tom Michelson, Patricia Jones, Kambou Olayani.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 376)
  - "Poetry from the City: Tom Michelson, Patricia Jones, Kambou Olayani.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 377)
  - "Poetry from the City: Tom Michelson, Patricia Jones, Kambou Olayani.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 378)
  - "Poetry from the City: George Washington University; Allen Ginsberg.", undated (Box 20A, Reel 379)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Judson Jerome interviewed on his farm in Hancock Maryland." Program aired 04/10/78., 09/1976 (Box 20A, Reel 380)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: The Negritude Poets; Lucille Clifton, Stanley Kunitz, Ellen Kennedy.", 10/1976 (Box 21A, Folder 381)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: The Negritude Poets; Lucille Clifton, Stanley Kunitz, Ellen Kennedy.", 10/1976 (Box 21A, Reel 382)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: The Negritude Poets; Lucille Clifton, Stanley Kunitz, Ellen Kennedy.", 10/1976 (Box 21A, Reel 383)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Elisavietta Ritchie.", 1977 (Box 21A, Reel 384)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Ambrosia Shepherd, editor of Messages from Black Women.", 02/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 385)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Ambrosia Shepherd, editor of Messages from Black Women.", 02/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 386)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Marvin Bell, a celebrated American poet. He teaches in Iowa at the Writer's MFA Program.", 02/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 387)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Marvin Bell, a celebrated American poet. He teaches in Iowa at the Writer's MFA Program.", 02/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 388)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Robert Cohen.", 02/07/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 389)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Robert Cohen.", 02/07/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 390)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Patrick Gavin, Ireland's Poet.", 02/13/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 391)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Patrick Gavin, Ireland's Poet.", 02/13/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 392)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Wilfred Cartey.", 02/19/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 393)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Wilfred Cartey.", 02/19/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 394)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Dr. Herman Ward.", 02/28/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 395)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Dr. Herman Ward.", 02/28/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 396)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Grace Cavalieri, Ahmos Zu-Bolton.", 04/08/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 397)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Four Women--Dierdra Baldwin, Ann Slayton Leffler, Nefrititi, Diana Vance.", 04/28/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 398)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Four Women--Dierdra Baldwin, Ann Slayton Leffler, Nefrititi, Diana Vance.", 04/28/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 399)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Terry Porter.", 05/05/1977 (Box 21A, Reel 400)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Terry Porter.", 05/05/1977 (Box 22A, Reel 401)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Akyaaba Kwabena, Addai Sebo.", 08/26/1977 (Box 22A, Reel 402)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Akyaaba Kwabena, Addai Sebo.", 08/26/1977 (Box 22A, Reel 403)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Samuel Allen is a well known Black poet, former civil rights activist, lawyer and professor of Black literature, who recorded this while visiting Washington.", 1978 (Box 22A, Reel 404)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Samuel Allen is a well known Black poet, former civil rights activist, lawyer and professor of Black literature, who recorded this while visiting Washington.", 1978 (Box 22A, Reel 405)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Allistair Patterson.", 02/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 406)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Allistair Patterson.", 02/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 407)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Joyce Varney.", 02/06/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 408)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Joyce Varney.", 02/06/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 409)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Charles Plymell.", 02/17/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 410)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Jean Rubin.", 02/27/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 411)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Jean Rubin.", 02/27/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 412)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Melissa Clark and Michael Cain.", 03/27/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 413)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Melissa Clark and Michael Cain.", 03/27/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 414)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Elizabeth Aldritch.", 05/22/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 415)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Elizabeth Aldritch.", 05/22/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 416)
  - "The Poem and the Poet: Linda Pastan.", 07/19/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 417)
  - "The Poem and the Poet: Linda Pastan.", 07/19/1978 (Box 22A, Reel 418)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: E. Ethelbert Miller.", 08/08/1978 (Box 23A, Reel 419)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: E. Ethelbert Miller, Thulani Davis, Greg Tate, Michelle Parkerson.", 09/26/1978 (Box 23A, Reel 421)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Antar Mberi.", 02/20/1979 (Box 22A, Reel 420)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: William Matthews.", 07/17/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 422)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: William Matthews.", 07/17/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 423)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Reza Baraheni, Iranian Poet.", 07/24/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 424)
    Notes indicate disclaimer is needed for language.
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Reza Baraheni, Iranian Poet.", 07/24/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 425)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Grace Cavalieri presents a Gwendolyn Brooks Special.", 07/31/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 426)
    Note: the interview is a repeat of the program from 1976 when Miss Brooks visited Washington D.C.
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Washington Writers Publishing House poets, Three new woman poets premiered in series 4, 1979.", 08/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 427)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Washington Writers Publishing House poets, Three new woman poets premiered in series 4, 1979.", 08/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 428)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Plow Women Rather than Reapers, an interview with author of This Feminist History.", 08/28/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 429)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Plow Women Rather than Reapers, an interview with author of This Feminist History.", 08/28/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 430)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Liam Rector.", 10/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 431)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Jane Flanders.", 10/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 432)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Annette Cap de Ville.", 12/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 433)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Gabrielle Edgcomb and The Sea Crane: Grace Cavalieri interviews two Washington women poets.", 12/09/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 434)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Gabrielle Edgcomb and The Sea Crane: Grace Cavalieri interviews two Washington women poets.", 12/09/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 435)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Robert Sargent, president of The Washington Writer's Publishing House, reads from his new book of poetry A Woman from Memphis.", 12/19/1979 (Box 23A, Reel 436)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: David Fisher, winner of the William Carlos Williams Award for the best book of poetry for 1978.", 01/29/1980 (Box 24A, Reel 437)
    32882015256095
  - "The Poet and the Poem: David Fisher, winner of the William Carlos Williams Award for the best book of poetry for 1978.", 01/29/1980 (Box 24A, Reel 438)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Vance Garnett, Valentine Poet." 02/13/??, undated (Box 24A, Reel 439)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Robert Sargent." 07/31/??, undated (Box 24A, Reel 440)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Robert Sargent." 07/31/??, undated (Box 24A, Reel 441)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Joanne Jimason, author of Naked Against the Belly of the Earth." 04/15/??, undated (Box 24A, Reel 442)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Karren Alenier." 08/19/??, undated (Box 24A, Reel 443)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Edouard Maunick, Negritude Poet.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 444)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Edouard Maunick, Negritude Poet.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 445)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Mary Mackey, California poet, in Washington on the occasion of her new book published by Gallimaufry press.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 446)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Richard Hart.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 447)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Richard Hart.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 448)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Ken Forde, Ladd, Jasha.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 449)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Ken Forde, Ladd, Jasha.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 450)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Donis Dondis.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 451)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Wilfred Cartey, the great Trinidadian poet, a blind poet.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 452)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Ann Darr, author of St. Ann's Gut, Myth of A Woman's Fist and Cleared for Landing.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 453)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Ann Darr, author of St. Ann's Gut, Myth of A Woman's Fist and Cleared for Landing.", undated (Box 24A, Reel 454)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: from Lorton Minimum Security Institution.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 455)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Ahmos Zu Bolton.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 456)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Ahmos Zu Bolton.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 457)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: John Pauker.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 458)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: John Pauker.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 459)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Dr. Kath Walker, Australian Poet.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 460)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Dr. Kath Walker, Australian Poet.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 461)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Dr. Herman Ward.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 462)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Dr. Herman Ward.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 463)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Dierdra Baldwin.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 464)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Dierdra Baldwin.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 465)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Reza Baraheni.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 466)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Reza Baraheni.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 467)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Sterling Brown.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 468)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Sterling Brown.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 469)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Sterling Brown.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 470)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Susan Wood.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 471)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Three Women; [E. Ethelbert Miller] Women Surviving Massacres.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 472)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Three Women; [E. Ethelbert Miller] Women Surviving Massacres.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 473)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Joseph Zaleka.", undated (Box 25A, Reel 474)
  - "Expressions: Dorothy Gilliam, Paul Robeson All American Biography.", 04/1977 (Box 26A, Reel 475)
  - "Expressions: New Directions in Black Literature; Jerry Ward discusses Black literature with Dr. Elinor Traylor and E. Ethelbert Miller.", 04/23/1977 (Box 26A, Reel 476)
  - "Expressions: New Directions in Black Literature; Jerry Ward discusses Black literature with Dr. Elinor Traylor and E. Ethelbert Miller.", 04/23/1977 (Box 26A, Reel 477)
  - "Expressions: New Directions in Black Literature; Jerry Ward discusses Black literature with Dr. Elinor Traylor and E. Ethelbert Miller.", 04/23/1977 (Box 26A, Reel 478)
  - "Expressions: New Voices in Prose, a program of short story readings--unpublished works.", 09/1977 (Box 26A, Reel 479)
  - "Expressions: Perry Alford, Prince Among Slaves.", 12/13/1977 (Box 26A, Reel 480)
  - "Expressions: Tom Dent interviewed by Jerry Ward.", 12/24/1977 (Box 26A, Reel 481)
  - "Expressions: Tom Dent interviewed by Jerry Ward.", 12/24/1977 (Box 26A, Reel 482)
  - "Washington Writer's Publishing House Poets.", 1978 (Box 26A, Reel 483)
  - "Expressions: Michael Harper.", 05/27/1978 (Box 26A, Reel 484)
  - "Expressions: Michael Harper.", 05/27/1978 (Box 26A, Reel 485)
  - "Expressions: David Ray.", 10/14/1978 (Box 26A, Reel 486)
  - "Expressions: Sam Westley's Poetry." 02/17/??, undated (Box 26A, Reel 487)
  - "Expressions: New Directions in Black Writing." 06/25/??, undated (Box 26A, Reel 488)
  - "Expressions: A conversation about this great poet; Herman Ward discusses Robert Frost.", undated (Box 26A, Reel 489)
  - "Expressions: A conversation about this great poet; Herman Ward discusses Robert Frost.", undated (Box 26A, Reel 490)
  - "Expressions: Pat Fahey with poets for multi-media happening.", undated (Box 26A, Reel 491)
  - "Expressions: Carolyn Kizer and Reed Whittemore discuss Pablo Neruda.", undated (Box 26A, Reel 492)
  - "Expressions: Wilfred Cartey at Howard University; dedicated to Leon Damas.", undated (Box 27A, Reel 493)
  - "Expressions: Wilfred Cartey at Howard University; dedicated to Leon Damas.", undated (Box 27A, Reel 494)
  - "Expressions: Wilfred Cartey at Howard University; dedicated to Leon Damas.", undated (Box 27A, Reel 495)
  - "Poets in Person: M.L.K. Library; Katharine Edgar, Robert Sargent.", 10/04/1976 (Box 27A, Reel 496)
  - "Poets in Person: M.L.K. Library; Katharine Edgar, Robert Sargent.", 10/04/1976 (Box 27A, Reel 497)
  - "James Dickey.", 1977 (Box 27A, Reel 498)
  - "James Dickey.", 1977 (Box 27A, Reel 499)
  - "Sterling Brown, a 30-minute poetry reading at the Textile Museum.", 1977 (Box 27A, Reel 500)
  - "Writer's Workshop on the Air: Our Favorite Poems and Poets.", 11/20/1977 (Box 27A, Reel 501)
  - "Michael Harper on Sterling Brown.", 1979 (Box 27A, Reel 502)
  - "Brimstone Poets.", 01/08/1985 (Box 27A, Reel 503)
  - "Sterling Brown Special at M.L.K. Library; Dr. Montague Cobb, A.B. Spellman, Leon Damas, May Miller, Walter Washington, Ossie Davis, Rubin Dee." 02/25/??, undated (Box 27A, Reel 504)
  - "Sterling Brown Special at M.L.K. Library; Dr. Montague Cobb, A.B. Spellman, Leon Damas, May Miller, Walter Washington, Ossie Davis, Rubin Dee." 02/25/??, undated (Box 27A, Reel 505)
  - "Sterling Brown Special at M.L.K. Library; Dr. Montague Cobb, A.B. Spellman, Leon Damas, May Miller, Walter Washington, Ossie Davis, Rubin Dee." 02/25/??, undated (Box 27A, Reel 506)
  - "Sterling Brown Special at M.L.K. Library; Dr. Montague Cobb, A.B. Spellman, Leon Damas, May Miller, Walter Washington, Ossie Davis, Rubin Dee." 02/25/??, undated (Box 27A, Reel 507)
  - "Folger Library Poetry Readings: David McAleavey, Geraldine Connolly, Maria Hobbs.", undated (Box 27A, Reel 508)
  - "Folger Library Poetry Readings: David McAleavey, Geraldine Connolly, Maria Hobbs.", undated (Box 27A, Reel 509)
  - "Robert Penn Warren; Library of Congress Press Conference.", undated (Box 27A, Reel 510)
  - "Gylan Cain.", undated (Box 27A, Reel 511)
  - "Michael Harper on Robert Hayden.", undated (Box 27A, Reel 512)
  - "Amiri Baraka.", undated (Box 28A, Reel 513)
  - "Mary Mackey.", undated (Box 28A, Reel 514)
  - Lucille Clifton.", undated (Box 28A, Reel 515)
  - Goethe Opening, undated; Series 1 (Box 28A, Reel 516)
  - Poet and the Poem: Jerome Judson interview, 1975-1976 (Box 71, Reel 612)
    A note on the box makes it difficult to understand if the interview took place in 1975 or 1976.
  - Dona Nobis Pacem, 03/02/1977 (Box 71, Reel 613)
    copyright held by Vivian Adelberg Rudow. "Composed for Ken Flynn, inspired by the Bronze Nun"
  - Robin Morgan and Grace Going Too Far, 05/20/1977 (Box 71, Reel 614)
  - Pacifica Washington by Grissby 7" Reel, 1977 August (Box 71, Reel 615)
  - The Poet and the Poem: William Matthews, 08/1977 (Box 71, Reel 4)
  - Grace Cavalieri at Bethesda Library, 1976-1977 (Box 71, Reel 616)
    Date on outside of box is 1977, but date on label on tape is 11-23-1976. Running time is 26:04
  - Americana Visited Variations by Vivian Adelberg Rudow, 1984 (Box 71, Reel 617)
  - The Poet and the Poem: Cavalieri and Robert Sargent at the Library of Congress, 08/20/1986 (Box 71, Reel 619)
  - Poet and the Poem: May Miller, 02/01/1987 (Box 71, Reel 618)
  - Addition to Best of Friends, 12/14/1987 (Box 71, Reel 620)
    Vivian Adelberg Rudow. box indicates this tape is II of II
  - Portrait Of A Friend, 01/1988 (Box 71, Reel 621)
    Vivian Adelberg Rudow
  - Rita Dove, 09/23/1993 (Box 71, Reel 622)
  - Poet and the Poem: Rita Dove, 08/1994 (Box 71, Reel 623)
  - Rita Dove Lecture, 10/06/1994 (Box 71, Reel 624)
  - The Poet and the Poem: Michael Glasser (Equalized), undated (Box 71, Folder 625)
  - Reed Whittemore, 10/19/1994 (Box 71, Reel 14)
  - OYELO Out Loud, 05/30/1996 (Box 71, Reel 626)
    could be Poet and the Poem
  - Migrations, 05/04/1997 (Box 71, Reel 627)
    note on original box: "Important tape (for Pacifica) original tape please do not lose) may 11 Poet and Poem
  - Rita Dove H.O., 05/18/1997 (Box 71, Reel 628)
    running time: 58:00
  - The Poet and the Poem: Lucile Clifton, undated (Box 72, Reel 629)
    date: February 9 - no year provided.
  - The Poet and the Poem: A.R. Ammons, undated (Box 72, Reel 630)
    date: May 21 - no year provided.
  - The Poet and the Poem: "Our listeners who are poets", undated (Box 72, Reel 631)
    from original box "1. An African Poet 2. 2 DC African American Poets with their variations on African American Poetry"
  - Pinecrest, undated (Box 72, Reel 632)
    copy of DAT original
  - Pinecrest reading, undated (Box 72, Reel 633)
  - Nancy and Ron Students, undated (Box 72, Reel 634)
  - Migrations, undated (Box 72, Reel 635)
  - [Joe McCabe?], undated (Box 72, Reel 636)
  - Dolores Kendrick, undated (Box 72, Reel 637)
    date: September 24 -no year provided.
  - S. Dunn, undated (Box 72, Reel 638)
    date: April 16-no year provided.
  - Sterling Brown, undated (Box 72, Reel 639)
    note on original box "Historical tape to be donated to G.W. Univ. Library protect please"
  - Sterling Brown original, undated (Box 72, Reel 640)
  - Frank Bidart, undated (Box 72, Reel 641)
    running time: 57:28
  - Whittemore, undated (Box 73, Reel 642)
  - [Waniak?], undated (Box 73, Reel 643)
  - Poet and the Poem: Fareedah Allah, undated (Box 73, Reel 644)
  - Sonia Sanchez, 02/16/1997 (Box 73, Reel 645)
  - Roland part 1 original, undated (Box 73, Reel 646)
  - Quincy Troupe Shaman Man, undated (Box 73, Reel 647)
    running time: 61 mins.
  - The Poet and the Poem: The She Company, undated (Box 73, Reel 648)
    date: July 7 - no year provided.
  - The Poet and the Poem: Ribbon of Song, undated (Box 73, Reel 649)
  - The Poet and the Poem: Ishmael Reed, undated (Box 73, Reel 650)
    date: November 17 - no year provided
  - The Poet and the Poem: Robert Pinsky, a poet laureate, 12/07/1995 (Box 73, Reel 651)
  - The Poet and the Poem: Hispanic poets, undated (Box 73, Reel 652)
  - The Poet and the Poem: Bob Hass, a poet laureate, undated (Box 73, Reel 653)
  - Feb comment #2, undated
    General
    Item currently missing.
  - sound track: Best of Friends, 1974 (Box 83, Reel 657)
    Vivian Adelberg Rudow; exceptions: Train, Merry go round, crowd from sound effects record
  - tape #3 poetry reading, undated
  - Cavalieri Heads Out, undated (Box 83, Reel 654)
  - Robt. Hayden The Poet and the Poem II, undated (Box 83, Reel 655)
    The tape box is marked 2 of 2
  - Soundings: Medieval English Politics and Poetry, 1988 August (Box 83, Reel 656)
  - Goethe opening, undated (Box 28A, Folder 516)
  - Harvest Kitchen, undated (Box 83, Reel 658)
    the tape box is also marked "solo cow + Arnsen"
  - Garth Tate and Staving Artist/Still Alive SA/SA, undated (Box 83, Reel 659)
    Tape box has label that lists 1.Music Lesson 2. Road Poem 3. Parmaribo 4. Heat. The box also mentions Essex Hemphill with Garth backup. The last poet is Garth
  - Reverb, undated (Box 83, Reel 660)
    note on tape "Ap. 7 8pm H.O. 50 minutes"
  - unidentified reel, undated (Box 83, Reel 661)
  - Master Tape for Side A of Cassette for Teaching Material (German Poets), undated; Series 1 (Box 101, Reel 669)
  - Master Tape for Side B of Cassette for Teaching Material (Poet and the Poem), undated; Series 1 (Box 101, Reel 670)
  - "The Poet and the Poem: Heinz Czechowski, Liosa Happel, Richard Wagner, Lane Jennings", 4/2/1995; Series 1 (Box 101, Reel 671)
- Videotape cassette, 1981-2005; Series 2
  Arranged alphabetically according to the program title, and then chronologically. Miscellaneous/unidentified videos are grouped at the end of the sequence under "Miscellaneous Recordings."
  This series consists of videotape cassettes in 120-minute VHS format. The tapes record poetry readings, interviews, award ceremonies, workshops, Grace Cavalieri's collaborative work with musician and composer Vivian Adelberg Rudow, and television programs such as "On the Go with AAUW," a public access television program produced by the American Association of University Women. Program titles also include "The Poet and the Poem," "American Poetry Live," "The Great Swamp Poetry Series."
  - The Poet and the Poem: "A Conversation with Richard Wilbur, Poet Laureate of the Library of Congress.", undated
  - 10th Annual Authors Recognition, 11/23/1992 (Box 58, Videocassette 1)
    Martin Luther King Memorial Library, Washington, D.C.
  - American Poetry live with Grace Cavalieri and Roland Flint [1/2], 10/1981 (Box 58, Videocassette 2)
    with inscription "Grace: sent 8/5/1=2003 - compliments of HoCoPoLitSo Remember this?
  - American Poetry live with Grace Cavalieri and Roland Flint [2/2], 10/1981 (Box 58, Videocassette 3)
  - Arts Alive "poetry reading", 12/01/1991 (Box 58, Videocassette 4)
  - Arts & Letters with Rachael Worby [1/2], 10/07/1996 (Box 58, Videocassette 5)
    Show #502 total length: 56:48
  - Arts & Letters with Rachael Worby [2/2], 10/07/1996 (Box 58, Videocassette 6)
  - ASTRAEA READING, 03/15/1991 (Box 58, Videocassette 7)
    Washington, D.C.
  - Being a Poet, undated (Box 58, Videocassette 8)
    FCAC Special 58:00 Producer: Martha [Mendenhall?]
  - Chapter 6 Baltimore the Open Window, undated (Box 58, Videocassette 9)
    Original
  - Come to My Garden, 1992 (Box 58, Videocassette 10)